<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Adam Li's blog - Personal</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2020</title><link href="/blog/2020/01/goals-2020/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-01:/blog/2020/01/goals-2020/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year was a great way to end what I like to call a decade of growth. These past 10 years, I went from high school to college. I found out the things I love, the things I hate and the things that I could care less about. Love came and went, along with different friends. Above all else, I am almost certain that I've found what I love to do. Science, and the ability to "make discoveries" that can help people are what I hope to do for the rest of my life. I came to graduate school without understanding why I wanted to be there, and where I wanted to go, but now I'm getting ready to leave... at least understanding why I came. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I am glad I found a partner that has been supportive of what I do, and patient enough to listen to my weird and obnoxious thoughts on things ranging from sleeping habits, to science. It has and should continue to be a thrilling experience to make mistakes, reflect and adapt while I face the next challenge of learning how to grow two minds at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm close to graduating from school where I will never have to "take courses" again, but rather then rejoicing that I never have to set foot in a classroom again, I'm realizing I'll miss the lessons in logic you learn from challenging yourself through homework and exams. I took up the Masters in AMS at JHU this year, and I'm glad I went through with it. I am close to publishing most of my thesis work this year and then going through the final defense of the PhD. It didn't seem so far away that I was struggling to understand the basic methodological papers my undergrad PI sent me, but now I'm confident to say that I at least understand 50% of things with a one time read. Time to grow and reflect on this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2019 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Learning Mandarin Chinese - Simplified [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Traveling to a Mandarin speaking country, Taiwan with my friends made me realize my Chinese is horrendous. I always went to China with my family, and I never had to get around by myself. This was the first time I wanted to rely on my Chinese to communicate with strangers, and get around the country, but I realized my speaking and reading ability is just not up to par. This year, I'm committed to speaking to my parents in as much Chinese as possible and I've even started a Wechat/Messenger/Line group chat with my Chinese friends to practice Chinese."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah this stopped after April when my friends Anthony and Justin stopped using Line chat lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Bartending Basic Drinks and Theory [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a bartending kit on Amazon and am aiming to learn how to make some basic drinks like an old fashioned, mojito and other drinks I can find online. Aiming to learn how to make 6 good drinks by the years end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely instead of doing this, I chose to not drink as much, ... so I guess that's an accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Continuation of Lifestyle Changes [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Cutting my own hair, benching 2 plates, reaching deadlift of 3 plates and running at least 5 miles per week. Been proud of myself for learning how to cut my own hair (thus saving time and money each month), and hitting a bench press of 2 plates, while still weighing 160 lbs. This year I hope to continue my fitness goals and potentially shave off 10-15 lbs to a flat 145-150 lb. This will be achieved with the help of my nifty Apple Watch Series 3."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still been cutting hair, but went all in on the high-rep, 1 plate for bench, deadlift and squat. I've been running a lot more recently and I think that will lead me to the goal-setting of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Professional Improvements and Consolidation of Technical Skills [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managed to get a lot of things done this year :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Improving Photography With New IG Page [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This year, I'm going to try to post new photos to a new instagram blog page with more travel related photos. This is to sort of separate my personal instagram from my photography hobby. I have a lot more to learn about optimal lighting and photography of different scenes (e.g. portraits, landscapes, nightshots). I am aiming to post an additional 12 photos that I am proud of onto this IG page by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link to keep up to dates with my adventure!
https://www.instagram.com/ajltravels/
"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn't happen as much as I wanted, but instead I worked with a few colleagues to get @EverydayBME off the ground, which is a super cool Instagram page off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2020 Goals:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Health: (Half-Marathon)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13.1 miles. Longer then I've ever ran in my life, but it's going to be the goal of this year, and the entrance into adulthood. In order to get to this point, say for the Boston half-marathon on October 13, 2020, then there will be a decent amount of training involved. I should set a goal to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] run 1-2 times per week with 4+ miles by March. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] run 1-2 times per week with 6+ miles by June. Run the Boston 10k in June.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] and then start training in July for the half-marathon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I measure side-effect success? Heart rate should ideally go to resting at 50 consistently. I should be stretching consistently and doing foam rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn another few signature dishes to maintain cooking health :).
- [ ] pancetta wrapped stuffed chicken w/ fetta cheese, spinach, mushrooms and garlic
- [ ] a red wine dish
- [ ] a fresh pasta dish&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Professional:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internship, or open-source development with at least 10 closed Issues and Pull Requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Personal:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think before speaking more, patience and focus on my friends, family and significant other more then myself. I've focused on my self-growth over the last 10 years, and it's time to focus on my external-growth over these next 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should check up on my family more often via WeChat, and give better presents for the birthday and holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should check up on my friends that don't live in Baltimore every few weeks or so. Put things on the schedule for hanging out. I should invite a few friends to do Montreal with me in the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should focus on listening to Sarah more this year. She's more right then I am in more instances then I would prefer to admit. The fallacy of trying to believe in yourself is that you convince yourself out of hubris that you are right even when you are wrong. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Europe - Living and Traveling</title><link href="/blog/2018/06/europe-summary-2018/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-06-01:/blog/2018/06/europe-summary-2018/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of my time abroad in Europe, 2017-2018.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick Background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top Experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culture EU vs America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Quick Background&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past year, I was fortunate to live in France, Europe from September 2017 till August 2018. While, I couldn't speak much French, I worked in an english speaking laboratory at Aix-Marseille Universite, under a really talented and successful professor, Dr. Viktor Jirsa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there, I had the chance to visit numerous countries and cities (I try to stay chronologically):
- London, UK
- Munich, Germany (Oktoberfest)
- Casablanca and Marrakech, Morocco
- Budapest, Hungary
- Geneva/Lausanne, Switzerland (LauzHack)
- Lyon, France
- Prague, Czech Republic
- Paris, France (Thanksgiving)
- Munich, Germany (with parents)
- Vienna, Austria
- London, UK (Christmas)
- Zurich, Switzerland (NY)
- Cambridge, UK (Cambridge Hacks)
- Berlin, Germany (Bosch Connected World Hackathon/Conference)
- Amsterdam, Netherlands (SD friends here)
- Paris, France
- Cassis, France (from Marseille)
- Amsterdam, Netherlands (Baltimore friends here)
- Barcelona, Spain
- Paris, France
- Saint Raphael, France (For TNG/INS Retreat! So fun...)
- Monaco
- Nice, France
- London -&amp;gt; Dublin, Ireland 
- Lisbon and Porto, Portugal
- London, UK (Last layover before heading home to USA)
- Tuscany and Pisa, Italy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Top Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switzerland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Southern France&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traveling A Lot
TBD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Culture EU vs America&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture in Europe is a huge mix of different nations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America is different because we are one nation with a mix of many nationalities that came to solely LIVE in America. Honestly, we're all American. I felt more American while living abroad, then Chinese because that's who I am; that's how I grew up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics of America in Europe is actually very well known. Everyone I knew heard about the major events in the USA. They knew a lot about Trump's policies and found it amusing that Americans had so many divisive issues that were not present in EU life. For example, they found it absurd that we have guns. Even if it is for enjoyment..., why do we need them? Even if you're a law-abiding citizen, why do you need a gun. EU citizens definitely don't see America as a great country in any aspect since Trump got elected. Most of the times the USA came up, it was with an air of humor, or mockery. To be fair, I agreed at times with them because Trump acted like a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Misc.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we share this interview in our social media posts?
Would you be okay with us writing small posts that may highlight different parts of this interview? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the most memorable part of your experience abroad?
(Telling a story and highlights of doing research abroad in an intl setting.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;traveling, connecting with people from other countries and going on a lab retreat EU style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the Whitaker experience improve your research in graduate school?
(relating their exp back to the Whitaker program)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it brought a different viewpoint into my research of epilepsy seizure localization. It also exposed me to the field of computational modeling and using dynamical systems to study biological phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For scientists planning on going abroad for a prolonged visit, what is some advice you would give them?
(giving some value to readers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;spend as much time as you can engaging in other researchers while you are there. Take as much time as you can to travel within the country and region also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you explain the research you undertook during your Whitaker in laymen terms and why it was important?
(education about the research to the general public that is digestable)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simulating seizures in the brain to determine if algorithms designed on empirical data can localize the origin of these seizures in-silico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="europe"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2019</title><link href="/blog/2018/01/goals-2019/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-01-07:/blog/2018/01/goals-2019/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another year has passed, and its getting harder and harder for me to distinguish the years from each other. Every new years goals post seems to be written just a few days ago in my head. This year was filled with transitions, both personal and professional. I started off the year living in France, and traveling to Switzerland to see how a NYE abroad would be like. The time abroad up until August was an experience that really taught me how to survive in a completely different country without a cohort of students around me, or a friend group from college for support. I did a lot of traveling in Europe, seeing countries and cities that I've never been to, such as Hungary, Portugal, Morocco and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professionally, I grew in ways that I did not expect. Rather then going to the EMBC conference with the rest of my lab, I went to a computationally focused neuroscience conference in Seattle. I reconnected with my high school friends and some old friends from JHU. The time there was perfect and a fond way for me to transition my life back into the USA. My time spent with the Theoretical Neurosciences Group helped me grow as an independent thinker and researcher. I developed a distinct appreciation for how mathematics can drive precise and beautiful descriptions of biological systems. I did some explicit exploration of using deep learning to understand its classification capabilities, and also see the pitfalls that occur when designing an architecture, or training scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2018 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Travel [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I traveled a lot last year. Currently this year, I've visited London, Paris, Lyon, Marrackech, Casablanca, Munich, Vienna, Prague, Budapest, Lausanne, Geneva, Cambridge, Nice, Monaco, Barcelona, Amsterdam, Lisbon, Porto, Tuscany, Qatar, Seoul, Busan, Hanoi, Lanhah Bay, Ho Chi Minh City and Columbus (Ohio). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my travel goals for this year are two parts:
i. I'm going to try to visit:
Lisbon [ ], 
Oslo [ ], 
Helsinki [ ], 
Stockholm [ ], 
Istanbul [ ], 
Athens [ ], 
Santorini [ ],
Croatia [ ], 
Luxembourg [ ], 
Bordeaux [ ], 
Berlin [ ], 
Frankfurt [ ], 
Rome [ ] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii. The things I'm going to try to attend are Tomorrowland 2018 [ ] and Yacht week 2018 [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Academic [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I submitted a conference paper on using research I did in France, using a computational modeling platform to study algorithmic performance of seizure localization in epilepsy patients. I submitted a poster for some preliminary work on combining training from empirical data and simulated data to improve seizure detection. This was a completely independent idea that I only had after spending some time working in France. I enrolled in Matrix Theory when I got back to JHU and really enjoyed delving deeper into the mathematical theory behind matrices and linear algebra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year holds a lot of potential. I'll be submitting a journal paper for a complete retrospective study on the fragility algorithm [ ], which will be part of my main thesis work. I'm going to be enrolled in Linear Systems Theory to understand more theory behind our work in the NCSL lab. I will also attempt to audit an optimization course with a focus on theory to better understand some of the core optimization algorithms that take place in machine learning and statistical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Professional [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to submit applications for internships, but I feel like research is always going on and interrupting the flow of things. My goal here was to submit applications to DE Shaw LLC, DE Shaw Research, Google Brain Research Team, DeepMind, Facebook Research, Amazon Data Science, Amazon Health Research. In all fairness, things were hectic with life as I had to transition between living in France back to JHU. I can still do this, but I hope that I can achieve that this fall, when things have settled at JHU and my PhD is nearing its end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python review of data structures [ ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Math review of machine learning basics, such as backpropagation, convolutional networks, lstm network, logistic regression, linear regression, expectation maximization scheme [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Personal [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wanted to do more photography, but my camera got stolen halfway into the year (RIP). However, I splurged and got an even better setup! The Sony a6500, will hopefully allow me to go even further with night shots, portraits and landscapes during this year. Also managed to hit benching of 225.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to reach a 
- a deadlift of 275 [ ] and 
- consistent running of 1-5 miles (by the end of the year) [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Cooking and Lifestyle [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed to start cooking a lot in France. Once I returned to JHU, I started cooking pretty lean at nighttime with a spinach, salmon and chicken breast with garlic combinations. I also started making kale smoothies on a daily routine, which has been a life changer. Who knew pumping your body with greens and some ginger in the morning, concealed with the sugar of frozen fruits would feel and taste so good?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Reading and Knowledge [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've tried to take on more reading about new topics that I find interesting, such as politics and blockchain technologies. I started using Pocket, which is a great resource for saving webpages for easy reading offline at a later time! Will continue to do so on topics related to blockchain scaling, right and left-wing politics, and machine learning in industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions for 2019:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Learning Mandarin Chinese - Simplified [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling to a Mandarin speaking country, Taiwan with my friends made me realize my Chinese is horrendous. I always went to China with my family, and I never had to get around by myself. This was the first time I wanted to rely on my Chinese to communicate with strangers, and get around the country, but I realized my speaking and reading ability is just not up to par. This year, I'm committed to speaking to my parents in as much Chinese as possible and I've even started a Wechat/Messenger/Line group chat with my Chinese friends to practice Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Bartending Basic Drinks and Theory [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a bartending kit on Amazon and am aiming to learn how to make some basic drinks like an old fashioned, mojito and other drinks I can find online. Aiming to learn how to make 6 good drinks by the years end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Continuation of Lifestyle Changes [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting my own hair, benching 2 plates, reaching deadlift of 3 plates and running at least 5 miles per week. Been proud of myself for learning how to cut my own hair (thus saving time and money each month), and hitting a bench press of 2 plates, while still weighing 160 lbs. This year I hope to continue my fitness goals and potentially shave off 10-15 lbs to a flat 145-150 lb. This will be achieved with the help of my nifty Apple Watch Series 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Professional Improvements and Consolidation of Technical Skills [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I'll be making a lot of strides in my professional career. On one hand, I'll be pursuing the development of a startup company that is a result of my PhD research. My PI and I will be developing a seizure localization software that outperforms anything on the market, or in academic research. Interestingly it is not based on deep learning ;). This means that I will have the opportunity to actually experience developing and designing software that complies with a 510K FDA approved software device. The software must be usable by clinicians, which will involve production level coding in Python. I look forward to learning while developing with our software engineering consultants (who definitely know more about production level coding). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the ideal goal is to be able to sell our technology by the years end to a larger EEG based company who can scale and distribute the technology into the clinic fast. Even if this doesn't happen, I believe there are still many important lessons to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this endeavor, I aim to showcase to myself and others that I am capable of designing and implementing a production level software system that can sit in a clinical center that pulls data, formats data properly, preprocesses it, runs an optimized parallelized algorithm for analysis and outputs high-grade visualizations that are clinically useful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I want to practice more of my coding skills with data structures and basic algorithms using LeetCode. So far, I've done 20-30 excercises and they are actually quite interesting to sit through. Upon reading the solutions, I always learn something new in terms of how to think like an experienced programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Improving Photography With New IG Page [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I'm going to try to post new photos to a new instagram blog page with more travel related photos. This is to sort of separate my personal instagram from my photography hobby. I have a lot more to learn about optimal lighting and photography of different scenes (e.g. portraits, landscapes, nightshots). I am aiming to post an additional 12 photos that I am proud of onto this IG page by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link to keep up to dates with my adventure!
https://www.instagram.com/ajltravels/&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2018</title><link href="/blog/2017/12/goals-2018/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-12-31:/blog/2017/12/goals-2018/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year has been a fantastic year from beginning to end. I turned the big 2 5 (yay 1 year older). However, this year came with a lot of fun as I spent time at Coachella 2017, made it out for birthdays of my friends in Vegas, spent time in SF, LA, SD and Chicago visiting old friends, enjoyed new time with Hopkins friends in NYC, Boston and DC, and spent a lot of time enjoying my "relative" last year in Baltimore. I was fortunate enough to win three prestigious fellowships: the NSF-GRFP, Whitaker and Chateaubriand fellowships. I presented two conference papers at two different conferences, where I was even able to make a trip through Korea and Japan come out of it. It's ending with me being in France working with the Theoretical Neurosciences Group in Marseille. I am incredibly fortunate to be working in a group of extraordinary people from all different countries and backgrounds. I am learning so much and developing new ideas that I honestly can't say I would've had if I were just back in Baltimore. I think I have some explicit goals this year related to my work because I find it fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2017 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Keep dance a significant part of my life: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is actually something I thought would impact me a lot. I still watch hella dance vids online and keep up with hip hop news here and there, but I haven't touched the dance floor in a few months and it almost feels normal now. I get my daily excercise and I'm driven by my research and learning opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Run a half-marathon: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah I don't know if this will ever happen... So maybe I'll aim to do a 5k next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Read four new books: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always learn from others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Establish a healthy workout regimen: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got to be able to deadlift 245, and bench 205 this year. I've also started working out in the morning, or at least daily. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Put myself in uncomfortable situations: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I moved to France and have been traveling my ass off. I don't intend on stopping and I've found that I started to become more comfortable with just being by myself. You really learn a lot when you have to handle everything from beginning to end without a friend/family member watching your back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Begin to learn French: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Duolingo and got to 2% fluency. Hell yeah. Well... I'm in France, so I started now LOL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Keep learning more "unrelated" math: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was so set on the idea of data science last year, but it's all related to my interest in medicine, tech, and AI. I've been reading more papers here and there about random things ranging from deep neural networks, matrix perturbation theory, to deep reinforcement learning. None directly relate to my rsearch, but it's fascinating and great to think about how it can continue to impact my research and future growth as a data scientist / engineer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Build 3 Node, JS, React webapps this year [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah I don't know why I thought this was feasible during a PhD. However, I've built a Node.js/D3.js web app at Lauz Hack this year! I'll be building my skills further as I design a complete system for data input, data analysis and data visualization for clinical usage within a Phase I clinical trial, that I will be helping lead in the next few years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2018 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Travel [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to be spending another 6-9 months in Marseille, France. I truly enjoy having this opportunity to live in Europe for not just one semester, but one year. However, I don't think I will ever choose to live here long term, so I want to take advantage of the majority of the time I have left here and go traveling... A LOT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently this year, I've visited London, Paris, Lyon, Marrackech, Casablanca, Munich, Vienna, Prague, Budapest, Lausanne, Geneva, Cambridge, Oxford, Whales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my travel goals for this year are two parts:
i. I'm going to try to visit:
Lisbon [ ], 
Oslo [ ], 
Helsinki [ ], 
Stockholm [ ], 
Nice [ ], 
Monaco [ ], 
Istanbul [ ], 
Athens [ ], 
Santorini [ ],
Croatia [ ], 
Barcelona [ ], 
Amsterdam [ ], 
Luxembourg [ ], 
Bordeaux [ ], 
Berlin [ ], 
Frankfurt [ ], 
Rome [ ], 
Bologna [ ], &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii. The things I'm going to try to attend are Tomorrowland 2018 [ ] and Yacht week 2018 [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Academic [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been able to finish two conference papers, and a journal paper as first author. I've also served as an author on two additional conference papers. This upcoming year, I want to delve deeper into the intersection of my current work with machine learning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to submit two conference papers: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on initial results of fragility tested on TVB and [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initial results of a DNN tested on TVB for seizure detection. [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to submit a journal paper for a complete retrospective study on the fragility algorithm [ ] and an Bayesian inference implementation of the final layer of prediction of the EZ set. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to enroll in a class on Matrix Theory, Stochastic Optimization and Nonlinear Optimization. These are three topics I feel like I have to understand at a deeper level to fundamentally be able to tackle many generic problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Professional [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the time is approaching when I will be thinking about graduation from the PhD program at JHU. It feels like a lifetime ago that I was a nervous wreck joining JHU and wondering if I was smart enough to keep up with some of the cutting edge research in BME. I think I still have some issues with where I feel in terms of knowledge. My goal is to augment and seal up those weaknesses / shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got my short term eyes set on a few companies and positions that I have heard great things about. I am excited at the possibility of learning even more by joining mathematics, free-thinking, machine learning and data expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal here is to submit applications to DE Shaw LLC, DE Shaw Research, Google Brain Research Team, DeepMind, Facebook Research, Amazon Data Science, Amazon Health Research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in order to make it within these groups, I should develop my fundamental computer science skills further by creating in C++ and Python the various data structures and Cracking the Code Interview problem sets. I should have a fundamental understanding of backpropagation, optimization, probability, statistics, and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ review of data structures [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python review of data structures [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Math review of backpropagation [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Math review of machine learning basics [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Personal [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've picked up photography and I enjoy just posting on Instagram/Facebook, photos that I take, that I like. I've stopped dancing, but I've started working out on a consistent basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to reach a 
- bench of 225 [ ], 
- a deadlift of 275 [ ] and 
- consistent running of 1-5 miles (by the end of the year) [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Cooking and Lifestyle [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be cooking at least 5 times a week, so that I can maintain a healthy diet. I will look at maintaining a combination of recipes and learning something new every other month! I'll keep an update here on the recipes I learn and experiment with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken Breast [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steak [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pasta With Meat [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salmon Dish [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuna Dish [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Fish Dish [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(if possible): Other seafood [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Reading and Knowledge [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to continuously be reading from highly regarded sources. I want to conssistently read from sources on Twitter, The World Economic Review and Bloomberg. I'll try to update some of my thoughts on the different mechanisms of obtaining knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep up with my intake of knowledge, I want to challenge myself to write a series of publically available blog posts on trends in technology, medicine, politics and economics/finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bitcoin [X]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ethereum/blockchain [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;machine learning/AI [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;politics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;foreign markets (EU/Asia) and cryptocurrency/blockchains [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emerging markets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2017</title><link href="/blog/2016/12/goals-2017/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-12-31:/blog/2016/12/goals-2017/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on one of the best years ever, I'm grateful for all the people and places that made these memories happen. I took some time around 1 year ago to plan out ten things I wanted to carry out in 2016. I've enjoyed it a lot because it's been a goal to work towards for the entire year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I want to look at what I set out to do, and where I've come in regards to those goals. It will be interesting to see how my own priorities simply a year ago changed throughout the year and what I want to keep and discard for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2016 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Spend more effort and time on good friends and ignore the rest. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Definitely did it with Vegas trips, Coachella, Asia traveling, San Francisco, Chicago and New York City. All were done with great friends that I would take a bullet for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Read more about politics and current events in our country. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- I think this year was a turmoil in the United States with Donald Trump having been elected. Personally, I was spurred to follow and read more news through Twitter, Facebook and news journal sites. Although I have yet to become an expert, it has definitely exposed me to thought leaders ranging from Democratic/Republican leaders to news journalists to high ranking company executives. I've begun formulating my own thoughts on the topic (which I won't go into) and I think it's really helped me think about what I want for my future, my family's future, my children's future and my country's future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Start choreographing again. [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Totally did not do this. Will have to put this on a higher priority list this year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Enter in 1-2 jams. [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hurt my ankle during the time frame when I could've definitely entered the jam at Johns Hopkins. I'm pretty disappointed though that I didn't try to do more while it was summer time and I was still relatively free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Begin taking photos and videos more during the year and documenting them. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I definitely had a late start this year by only doing this towards the end of 2016, but I'm definitely getting more into it. I've learned the basics of manipulating aperture, shutter speed and angles. It's really fun and I'm surprised by how excited I get over good photos and photo opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Continue blogging about graduate school and the milestones of a PhD in STEM. [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think logging experiences in graduate school are important, but more important are reaching those milestones. I've realized how tough different aspects of the PhD are and I think for 2017 I would want to focus more effort on tangibly meeting milestones in graduate school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Run a half-marathon: Rock &amp;amp; Roll Half Marathon in SD/DC [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got lazy and then my ankle got hurt, but I definitely want to try again for 2017!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Spend less time on myself and volunteer more. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- I don't think I've done this at all, but in a different interpretation I've focused more on making an impact outside of research. I'm very excited to say that I started HEME (Hopkins Engineering Medicine Exchange) with one of my close friends in graduate school and I have big dreams for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;9. Spend less time on social media (Facebook and Snapchat). [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't do a great job towards the beginning because I think as all millennials are, I was addicted to seeing how other people's lives were progressing. However, simply today, one of my good friends showed me a video I think is worth sharing. (https://www.facebook.com/deltaprotective/videos/10157890106040640/?hc_ref=NEWSFEED) I want to spend even less time by keeping "Kill News Feed" and using Instagram/Facebook simply to log photographs I take and memories I want to engrave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Be content with paying my dues. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think this year I started to examine what excites me in life and what excites me about the future. It definitely isn't working at some corporate 9-5 job (even if I think the job is "impactful"). It's innovating and pushing the bounds of medicine using engineering, mathematics and computer programming. These topics are what excite me, while medicine is what spurs me to make a difference. I'm looking forward to spending ~5 (hopefully) years at Johns Hopkins absorbing different learning experiences and getting my Masters in Applied Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics while I'm also there. Why not get a free additional education with the PhD while I'm there?
6/10 kinda. I guess not bad :p.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New 2017 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Keep dance a significant part of my life: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I might not be able to choreograph a piece, participate in jams and get involved in dance photography, I want to simply keep bboying, keep taking choreo classes and keep my camera/gopro at all major dance events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Run a half-marathon: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to start running couple miles at the gym every other day and hopefully do one in the spring :).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Read four new books: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This year, I've managed to read ~4 books due to a book club established with my friends and I. It's made me more engaged in my own self development because I spent less time on social media and video games before sleeping. I want to do it again with or without another book club.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Establish a healthy workout regimen: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Been exercising at the gym more this year and I'm pretty happy with where I've gotten. I think being able to deadlift 245 and bench 225 are solid goals to have for this year. While continuing dancing, I hope to live a healthier lifestyle. In addition, this could entail just eating healthier through (salad every other day and cooking most nights that I have time).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Put myself in uncomfortable situations: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think this last one encompasses a number of things I think I need to go through. Although my friend circles aren't the same in Baltimore as in California, there are people I meet everyday that offer unique perspectives. Engaging in making relations is the first one. I haven't really explored doing "activities" for fun, such as hiking and exploring. I want to put myself out there and go on more "naturey" activites. I've had a lot of fun doing that in the past couple of months and I think it will only improve when I go into 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Begin to learn French: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using duolingo and trying to put myself out there with possibly a solo adventure to Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Keep learning more "unrelated" math: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In my research I have a very focused area that I am developing, but I want to become a thought leader in data science one day. The only way to do that is to continue my reading of papers unrelated to my research and continue my textbook reading of different topics, such as matrix theory and bayesian statistics. The more I understand, the more I might even be able to apply to my PhD research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Build 3 Node, JS, React webapps this year&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping it under 10 this year because I recently read about Warren Buffet's 5/25 rule and am inspired by its logic. Happy 2017 everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2016</title><link href="/blog/2015/12/goals-2016/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-12-31:/blog/2015/12/goals-2016/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Each year passes by faster and faster in my opinion, so I want to make the most out of 2016. As 2016 comes and 2015 comes to a close, I want to make some resolutions and goals for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more effort and time on good friends and ignore the rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I realized that even someone who you've known for years can exit your life in an instant. I want to spend more time and money on people that are there for you when you're up and down. When shit went down for me, people who I thought I could count on were nowhere to be seen. Why waste time and effort on those people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about politics and current events in our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that coming from California is a blessing in many ways. However, I think that we take for granted all the things we have. There is a lot of different things happening around the country (e.g. politics) that I did not educate myself on. Using politico and pulse apps to keep up to date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start choreographing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout undergrad, I made excuses for not trying more in dance to improve. Whether it was coursework, social life, or laziness, I didn't put in time and effort into my passion. Will try to do at least 1 piece and work on it throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter in 1-2 jams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been bboying for almost 8 years and it has carried me through undergrad and high school. Want to continue going for top 8 in some big jams until I can't bboy anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin taking photos and videos more during the year and documenting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad gave me his old Nikon D5000 and I got a GoPro at the beginning of the summer. Photography is a way for me to keep involved in the hip hop scene once I can't dance anymore. Videos and photos are also great of documenting the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue blogging about graduate school and the milestones of a PhD in STEM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of challenges and obstacles to overcome to get to a PhD program. There are also many to overcome whilst in the program. I want to talk about various events including: preparing for grad school in undergrad, applying for grad school, applying for fellowships, picking your rotations, picking your coursework, picking your advisor, choosing a thesis committee, structuring and studying for your DBO and then research on a daily basis. My goal is to graduate from this PhD as soon as possible (ideally 4-5 years) and start working to get industry experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run a half-marathon: Rock &amp;amp; Roll Half Marathon in SD/DC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been saying that I wanna do this for years... time to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend less time on myself and volunteer more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spent too much time saying I wanna help out and not enough time doing. Getting involved in THREAD at Baltimore is one step and I hope to do more. The world is too big to just always be working on yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend less time on social media (Facebook and Snapchat).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good for seeing friends and chatting. Good for sending some updates once in awhile and documenting photos/videos. Not good for productivity. Aim: go from online once/day to once/two days this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be content with paying my dues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've always been anxious to accomplish things. However, over the next 4 years, I realized it'll be grind and work. Gaining the technical skills so I can set myself up for maximizing the probability of succeeding in a technical startup. Just have to be patient and have this same dream when I'm 29.
All resolutions are goals in my opinion. The only real way to accomplish a goal that you set your mind to is work on them in minimal increments. Happy new years. It's going to be a good one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry></feed>