<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Adam Li - Travel</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/travel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Travel - Marseille</title><link href="/blog/2017/09/travel-marseille/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-09-22:/blog/2017/09/travel-marseille/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of how to visit Marseille and get the most out of your trip.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Europe - Marseille, France&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;
- General Suggestions
    - Sights
    - Food
    - Nightlife/Drinking
    - Getting Around
- FAQ
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;General Suggestions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know your geography in Japan. Since everything is easily accessible by high speed train, you can plan your trip by region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Airports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marseille Provence Airport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basilique Notre-Dame de la Garde
A huge castle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musee des Civilisations d'Europe
A really cool looking museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cathedral La Major
Big cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vieux Port
A docking port that has a lot of tourists and boats. Nice place to walk around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les Calanques
A hiking trail and place to go to check out a sick view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parc Longchamp
Cool park&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orange Velodrome
soccer stadium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chateau d'lf
An island fortress and former prison &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frioul Archipelago
An island 8 km off the coast of Marseille.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I briefly describe a couple of food places that are worth the HYPE. For locations, just use google, or yelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to get around each city would definitely be using the train/metro. It is perfectly affordable, but if you're running late, you can easily get a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a taxi (and you don't have the japanese app), you can always ask the restaurant/bar/store you are at to order a taxi. They are always perfectly happy to call the taxis for you using their app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q: How do I get around?
A: I highly suggest getting the Kansai pass ahead of time if you are going to be traveling in that region. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="europe"></category><category term="france"></category><category term="marseille"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel - Asia</title><link href="/blog/2017/08/travel-asia/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-08-04:/blog/2017/08/travel-asia/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A walkthrough of my experience in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Asia&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;South Korea&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seoul Summer 2017 | July 8 - July 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shanghai Summer 2016 | June 13 - June 23&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;South Korea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Seoul Summer 2017 | July 8 - July 15&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical Sightseeing Places:
Namsan Tower - I went at nighttime and the views were really great! It's also where all the couples put their locks on a fence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwanghwamun Palace and Gyeongbukgong Palace - if you're into historical stuff, these are some old temples you can check out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bukchon Village - a small traditional village with cute boutiques and restaurants that you can walk around if you want to get away from the super modern shopping areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han River - it's nice to just sit along the river and have a picnic, or you can rent bikes and bike along the river too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheonggyecheon Stream - also one of my favorite places. The stream is all lit up at night so it's very nice to stroll around there at night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Namdaemun Market - super cheap street market where you can get souvenirs, bags, clothes, etc. Kind of random but if you wear glasses they are also well known for having cheap glasses! I got a new pair of frames+lens for like $60 and they made it for me within an hour or so!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragon Hill Spa - if you want to have the spa experience that you always see in kdramas, this is one of the largest spas in Korea (I think there are like 7 stories) and I remember they can speak Chinese/English so it wasn't too hard to communicate. Also they sell fried chicken on one of the floors and its really good!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shopping:
Hongdae - one of my favorite places in Korea! There's a lot of talented street performers (dancers, singers) so it's cool to see that side of Korean culture. Also there's a few cat cafes here, and also a trickeye museum which was really fun if you want to take trippy photos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myungdong - perfect to get all your shopping done in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;China&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shanghai Summer 2016 | June 13 - June 23&lt;/h3&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="asia"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel - Baltimore</title><link href="/blog/2017/08/travel-baltimore/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-08-04:/blog/2017/08/travel-baltimore/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A walkthrough of my experience in Baltimore.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Baltimore, MD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Suggestions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting Around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FAQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;General Suggestions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peabody Library:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inner Harbor:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National Aquarium:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fort Mchenry:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miss Shirley's Cafe:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woodberry Kitchen:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chocolate Over Water:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abbey's Burger House:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LP Steamers:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fell's Point:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federal Hill (Fed Hill):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mt. Vernon:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber/Lyft are incredibly cheap within this city. I would use this solely because the subway system is not that great and the bus system isn't ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the circulators are generally free if you are just looking to get a free ride from Hopkins -&amp;gt; Inner Harbor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Where should I stay? 
A: I would try to stay at Inner Harbor, Fed Hill, or Canton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: I only have a day in Baltimore, where should I go?
A: Miss Shirley's, Woodberry Kitchen, and Chocolate Over Water to eat. Inner Harbor and the National Aquarium to see. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="baltimore"></category><category term="usa"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel - Chicago</title><link href="/blog/2017/08/travel-chicago/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-08-04:/blog/2017/08/travel-chicago/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A walkthrough of my experience in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Chicago, Illinois, USA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Suggestions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting Around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FAQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;General Suggestions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Airports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to/from the airport, you can take the metro, which is only about $3. Else, you can take uber/lyft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Hare Airport: &lt;br /&gt;
This is the main airport that is a lot larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway Airport: &lt;br /&gt;
This is the main airport that services Southwest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Cloud Gate / Millenium Park: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the home of the infamous Chicago Bean. The entire area has very cool architecture, and there is a snake bridge that goes over the highway that leads to a park. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend coming to check out the Bean once during the day and once in the late afternoon. The different lights provide for a truly appreciative experience. If you're into checking out cool parks, go to the playground that is across the snake bridge. There's an incredible playground built for kids, but it's a great experience to relive your childhood making your way through the slides, tree houses and swings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Art Institute of Chicago: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would highly recommend if you're into art. A great collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Chicago Architecture River Tour: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is advertised all over the city. A ticket costs ~$35 and you go on a large boat that will take you on a guided tour throughout the river and talk about some of the history of Chicago and its beautiful architecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the price seems hefty, it's a great thing to try at least once (hell, I've gone twice and loved it both times). I would definitely recommend trying this in the warmer seasons because it can get unbearably cold outside on the boat deck. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Willis Tower / Sears Tower:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was at one point the tallest building in the USA and houses the infamous glass cube. You've probably seen a bunch of your friends Instagram this. If you're afraid of heights, it might not be the best idea. However, it definitely makes for a cool sight and is worth the trip at least once. 
It does cost quite a bit of money to go up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Lincoln Park Zoo: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently this is free, so why not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Crown Fountain: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to Cloud Gate, you just have to venture a bit south to reach this beautiful sight. It's essentially a huge fountain that is great to take photos of. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Navy Pier: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pier that you can walk around, which houses a ferris wheel and a bunch of other amusement park rides. It's a great walk during the warmer seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. River Walk: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incredible area is essentially a walkway along the river of Chicago. It takes you from the Trump Tower all the way down the river, and is an incredible place to walk during the daytime as well as night time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take note, that there is a closing time for the river walk at night (~11PM), so I would go around 9 if you want to grab some great night shots of Chicago!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I briefly describe a couple of food places that are worth the HYPE. For locations, just use google, or yelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Deep Dish Pizza: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has heard about the infamous Chicago deep dish pizza. Well if you're into pizza, meat, cheese and sauce, then it's really worth the hype. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The places that are well worth the try are:
1. Lou Malnati's
2. Giordano's
3. Pizzeria Uno &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to decide which one is the best, but for my personal preference I like them in this order because Lou generally has a better crust. It's more crunchy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Garrett's Popcorn: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a famous popcorn place that sells all different kinds of popcorn. You name it; they probably have it. Everything from caramel, chocolate covered, to regular popcorn, Garrett's has it all. This is great for souvenirs for friends/family/coworkers because they sell them either in traditional popcorn bags, or in to-go containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Purple Pig: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is by far one of my most favorite restaurants in all of USA. It's a tapas place (family style sharing of small plates), so definitely try to come with a group. There is generally a wait, so I would recommend putting your name down early around dinner opening, or lunch opening, and then possibly going and walking along the RiverWalk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll leave it to Yelp to advise you on what to eat because truly everything there is worth your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Girl on the Goat: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also by far one of my most favorite restaurants in all of USA. It's a tapas place (family style sharing of small plates), so definitely try to come with a group. It's slightly more upscale and more expensive then the Purple Pig. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would advise MAKING A RESERVATION well before your trip. If you have a large group, there is no way you will get seated if you are only in town for a few days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll leave it to Yelp to advise you on what to eat because truly everything there is worth your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Wildberry Cafe: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite brunch place. It's right next to Cloud Gate / Millenium Park. Hands down, make sure you try their specialty pancakes and pretty much everything else on the menu is great. There will always be a wait, so you can put your name down and then go check out Millenium Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll leave it to Yelp to advise you on the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. The Mid: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a night club that houses some DJs from time to time (e.g. I saw Dash Berlin here once).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Sound Bar: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also a night club that houses some DJs from time to time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Three Dots and a Dash: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a speakeasy that has very instagram/snapchat worthy drinks. It's worth checking out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Signature Room: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not willing to pay to go up to Willis Tower, you can come here to grab a drink and get a free view of Chicago. It's great to see both during the day and at night because of Chicago's night lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. JPark Rooftop Bar: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a rooftop bar that is just a great place to chill and relax. You can place reservations if you have a large group, so make sure to do that, else it can get crowded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Goose Island Brewery: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heard it's good. I'll have to check it out and leave my comments here sometime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the advent of Uber/Lyft, you could definitely get around by just walking and taking the subway. There is a 'blue line' that is open 24/7, which is AMAZING. Chicago sells 3 day all-you-can-ride tickets for $20, but to be honest with Uber/Lyft, you can easily get around and save a lot more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to/from the airports, you can easily take the subway lines to wherever you're staying. I would recommend this over Uber/Lyft because it's only a few dollars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're downtown, generally you can walk everywhere. So I would advise just using the subway to/from the airport and then Uber/Lyft with your group elsewhere. Obviously if you're solo traveling, I would probably get a multi-day subway pass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Images in Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="test" src="photos/chicago/atoma.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="test" src="{attach}chicago/atom.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Where should I stay? 
A: Generally, I'm an advocate of staying downtown because then everything is walking distance. If not, I would try to stay within walking distance to a subway station. Stay away from South Chicago because that is a very crime-ridden area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: I only have a day in Chicago, where should I go?
A: Purple pig, Girl on the goat, Lou Malnati's to eat. Cloud Gate / Millenium Park and the River Walk to see. Signature Room for a night time drink if you have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="chicago"></category><category term="usa"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel - East Coast</title><link href="/blog/2017/08/travel-east-coast/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-08-04:/blog/2017/08/travel-east-coast/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A walkthrough of my experience in East Coast.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;USA East Coast&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baltimore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Washington DC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New York City&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boston&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Baltimore&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Washington DC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New York City&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Boston&lt;/h2&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="east coast"></category><category term="usa"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel - Europe</title><link href="/blog/2017/08/travel-europe/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-08-04:/blog/2017/08/travel-europe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A walkthrough of my experience in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Partner Banks
Chase doesn't have any unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make list of places I want to go:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look into swiss alps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look into iceland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;portugal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cambridge, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jungfraujoch for half fare card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barclays United Kingdom (England, Scotland, Wales, Northern Ireland, Jersey, Guernsey and the Channel Islands)
ABSA (South Africa)
BNP Paribas (France)
BNL D'Italia (Italy)
Deutsche Bank (Germany and Spain)
UkrSibbank (Ukraine)
TEB (Turkey)
Scotiabank (Canada, Mexico, Peru, Chile, and the Caribbean countries: Anguilla, Antigua &amp;amp; Barbuda, The Bahamas, Barbados, British Virgin Islands, Cayman Islands, Dominica, Dominican Republic, Grenada, Jamaica, St. Maarten, Puerto Rico, Saint Kitts &amp;amp; Nevis, Saint Lucia, St. Vincent &amp;amp; The Grenadines, Trinidad &amp;amp; Tobago, Turks &amp;amp; Caicos Islands, and US Virgin Islands)
Westpac Bank (Australia and New Zealand)
China Construction Bank (Mainland China, excluding Hong Kong)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://locators.bankofamerica.com/international.html&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="europe"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel - Japan</title><link href="/blog/2017/07/travel-japan/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-26:/blog/2017/07/travel-japan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A walkthrough of my experience in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Asia&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;
- General Suggestions
    - Sights
    - Food
    - Nightlife/Drinking
    - Getting Around
- FAQ
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;General Suggestions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know your geography in Japan. Since everything is easily accessible by high speed train, you can plan your trip by region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Airports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo:
1. Narita airport
This is the main international airport near Tokyo. To get to and from here, you can take the Narita express for ~30,000 yen ($30 USD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haneda airport
This is the domestic airport near Tokyo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osaka
1. Kansai airport
This is the main airport near Osaka. It is easy to get to and from here using the metro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osaka:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kyoto:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nara:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I briefly describe a couple of food places that are worth the HYPE. For locations, just use google, or yelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to get around each city would definitely be using the train/metro. It is perfectly affordable, but if you're running late, you can easily get a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a taxi (and you don't have the japanese app), you can always ask the restaurant/bar/store you are at to order a taxi. They are always perfectly happy to call the taxis for you using their app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q: How do I get around?
A: I highly suggest getting the Kansai pass ahead of time if you are going to be traveling in that region. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="japan"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel - Korea</title><link href="/blog/2017/07/travel-korea/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-26:/blog/2017/07/travel-korea/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A walkthrough of my experience in Seoul.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Seoul, South Korea&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Suggestions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting Around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FAQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;General Suggestions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I briefly describe a couple of food places that are worth the HYPE. For locations, just use google, or yelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nightlife/Drinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Where should I stay? 
A: Generally, I'm an advocate of staying downtown because then everything is walking distance. If not, I would try to stay within walking distance to a subway station. Stay away from South Chicago because that is a very crime-ridden area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: I only have a day in Seoul, where should I go?
A: Purple pig, Girl on the goat, Lou Malnati's to eat. Cloud Gate / Millenium Park and the River Walk to see. Signature Room for a night time drink if you have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="korea"></category></entry></feed>